It's a lost cow.
It has to be a lost cow, doesn't it?
When you write snail with kanji, you write the kanji for cow, right?
Take the first symbol from whirlpool, change the water radical into an insect one, add cow, and you have snail.
You hear of countless types of things that will confuse people, but...
in your situation, and that bit you said about a snail, it definitely has to be a lost cow, right?
It's around here.
Huh?
It should be around here: the house where I lived.
House? Isn't this just a road?
District reshuffling.
Not even a year has passed and already it has become like this.
We already sold it, and I didn't really think the house would remain...
And yet, this is quite depressing.
Yeah, isn't it?
Time is wasted on something that can't be helped.
Let's go, Araragi-kun.
Are you done already?
Done.
I see.
Let's go, Hachikuji.
It's about time you let go of my leg, Hachikuji.
It's difficult for me to walk.
Say something. Don't be so quiet.
It's not like I want to be stuck to your disgusting legs like a louse!
You're mean! I'm reporting this to the PTA!
The PTA?
The PTA is a very incredible organization, you know.
A minor like you with no influence: your life hangs in the balance!
With a single finger, they'll go "pop" and it'll be over!
A single finger, huh? That's pretty scary.
By the way, Hachikuji, what does PTA stand for?
That's...
PTA is the abbreviation of Parent Teacher Association.
That means it's an association for parents and teachers.
It can also stand for the surgical method percutaneous transluminal angioplasty. That's medical jargon.
I doubt that's the answer you were looking for.
Under these circumstances, the Parent Teacher Association should be the correct explanation.
My, aren't you knowledgeable.
It's you who's ignorant and incompetent, Araragi-kun.
The word "ignorant" has a nice ring to it, so I don't mind being called that,
but "incompetent" is going just a bit too far...
Is that so?
Then I'll just use "pathetic" next time.
By the way, Hachikuji...
What is it, Araragi-san?
What exactly is the place that this address is referring to?
I'm not telling.
I choose to remain silent.
I won't take you there if you don't tell me.
I didn't ask for your help. I can go alone.
But you lost your way.
So what?
Hachikuji, umm...
For the sake of younger generations, I'll tell you that relying on others is okay.
Sure, that's fine for you, with your low self-esteem.
Go ahead and wear yourself out relying on others,
but I don't have a need to do such a thing.
To me, this is as simple as using an everyday vending machine!
Fixed selling price?
I understand, mistress.
I beg of thee.
Please tell me what may be found at the place indicated by this address.
Your words are insincere.
If she were either of my two sisters, she would have been tricked upon hearing it.
Looks like methods used to treat stupid kids do not work on her.
Seriously, what should I do?
Mistress, have some allowance.
Oh, goody! I'll tell you anything!
I see it's a stupid kid.
A person named Tsunade-san lives there.
Oh?
What's your relationship?
A relative.
Relative, I see.
At least during Mother's Day you must practice filial piety at home.
Because you're always like this...
Because of this, no matter how long...
I don't want to be taught a lesson by you.
No, what do you know?
Somehow, I know.
You were the one sitting on a park bench and spacing out this Sunday morning.
That isn't what a normal person would do.
No, I was only...
Touring.
Tworing?
How cool!
Well, I'm actually only using my bicycle.
I see.
Speaking of tworing, it should indeed be a motorbike.
What a pity...
It's because school rules forbid students to take driving tests for motorbike licenses.
But regardless, motorbikes are dangerous.
I prefer cars.
I see.
But that's fourring.
This person has amusingly mixed up the meaning of touring.
By the way, the roads here are really complicated.
You have some guts to come here alone.
Well, it's not the first time I've been here.
It isn't? Then how did you get lost?
I haven't been here for a long time.
By the way, Arararagi-san...
You included an extra "ra."
Sorry. I stuttered...
Don't say my name in such a disgusting way...
It can't be helped.
Anybody will have times when they say something wrong.
Don't tell me that you've never stuttered before.
I can't say I haven't,
but it never happened when I said another person's name.
Then...
Say "Basugasubakuhatsu" thrice.
That isn't a person's name.
It is a person's name.
I know at least three people with that name.
That's why it's safe to say that it's a fairly common name.
Basugasubakuhatsu, Basugasubakuhatsu, Basugasubakuhatsu...
The creature that devours dreams is...?
Baku?
Wrong answer.
Creatures that eat dreams are...
humans.
Don't act smart!
Hey, Araragi-kun.
Huh?
Could you tell me the address again?
Okay, let me take a look.
It seems like we've passed here before.
Eh? Have we?
If you want to blame me, go ahead.
No. I won't blame you for such a minor thing.
I see.
Why are you so afraid of Senjougahara?
She seems to hate me.
I can feel the strong aura coming from her body saying, "What a hindrance! Get lost somewhere!"
Not to that extent, right?
Hey, Senjougahara.
What?
Do you hate kids?
I hate them. I really do.
They should all die.
Because I totally don't know how to get close to a kid.
It was during middle school, I think.
I came out of the department store after buying some things and bumped into a kid around 7 years old.
Ah, and he cried?
No, it's not the problem of crying.
I said to the 7 year old kid at that time...
"Are you all right?"
"Are you hurt?"
"I'm terribly sorry."
Because I really didn't know how to face kids, I was shocked and made a mistake.
But to actually make me bow down and grovel...
I was shocked.
From then on, those existences called "children," be they humans or otherwise,
I have hated and been cautious of.
By the way, Araragi-kun...
What?
It seems like we've gone too far again.
Eh, the residence?
This is the second time, hey.
If you are capable, please blame me however you like.
No, I won't blame you over such a small thing...
Eh, Senjougahara.
Didn't you already say that earlier?
Ah, is that so?
What's wrong?
Ah, right.
Didn't you say it's due to district reshuffling that you lost your way?
No, it's not.
It's not like all the roads from before are gone.
It isn't because of the structure that we're lost.
What are you doing?
I plan to use the GPS navigation system.
Oh?
Eh?
What's the matter?
All of a sudden, it's out of range.
This is...
I guess this won't work.
Ah?
I can't find it no matter how many times I walk here.
Hachikuji?
I'm always walking toward nowhere.
I can't reach my mother's side.
Because I'm a lost snail...
We, who couldn't find the destination no matter what, consulted Oshino.
Do you know where it is?
If you're not sure, then maybe I should go.
To have you worried that my memory will reach your level...
I'm not the least happy about it.
I should say that I'm extremely depressed.
Is that so?
By the way...
Don't leave me alone with that child.
After hearing my strange exchange with Senjougahara,
she seems to have tensed up again.
Say, you mentioned something about your mother, right?
Isn't that "Tsunade" person a relative?
Hachikuji-chan, I will treat you to ice cream next time, so could you come closer?
Let's go!
Then, coming back to what I said just now, your mother is...
A mother is also considered a type of relative, right?
Well, that may be correct, but...
Besides, even if you say "mother," regretfully it isn't like that anymore.
Ah...
Tsunade was my surname before third grade.
After living with my father, it was changed to Hachikuji.
Seriously? I actually put on an adult look, saying things like, "Practice filial piety."
No, I didn't come here just because it's Mother's Day.
I'll head toward my mother's place whenever I get the chance.
I see.
But, no matter how many times I search for it, I still can't find it.
That's when you met that snail?
I'm not too sure if I have met it.
You look as if you've had many painful encounters.
Ouch, ouch!
You damned imp!
What are you doing?!
Ouch, it hurts.
It hurts like hell!
Ah...
No, I can't seem to laugh it out.
A repeated victory will lead to one feeling empty.
There stood a high school boy, who for selfish reasons...
had twice beaten an elementary school girl unconscious, and had gotten all nihilistically
worked up about it.{小学生女子を二回も殴りつけ、自信させた挙句に
Actually, that's still me.
Your expression is really scary, Araragi-kun.
Ha-Hanekawa.
A look of shock.
That expression is much better.
What's wrong? What are you doing here?
I was just killing time.
I see.
I'm also here to kill some time.
I can't stay put at home. Sunday is the day I go for walks.
I feel that you worry too much...
Say, by the way, Araragi-kun.
Is that child your sister?
It's a girl who got lost.
Her name is Hachikuji Mayoi.
Hachikuji? I heard of it in the Kansai region.
By the way, the shrine which appeared in The Tales of Shinonome is called...
Ah, even though it's said to be that, the kanji is written differently.
You sure know everything, don't you?
It's not that I know everything. I just know what I know.
Hello, Mayoi-chan.
I'm a friend of this boy. My name is Hanekawa Tsubasa.
Don't speak to me. I hate you.
It seems that I'm hated.
There, there.
Mayoi-chan, you are so cute.
I just want to eat you up!
But you can't bite this boy's hand all of a sudden, okay?
Here, you should apologize.
Sorry, Araragi-san.
And you can't be like that, okay?
What do you mean? You're referring to violence, right?
Violence is naturally wrong.
But after beating a child, it's not right if you don't explain the reason she was beaten.
Speaking to you really has its benefits.
By the way, did she lose her way around here?
If that's the case, I may be able to lead the way.
Well, Senjougahara just went to find someone...
Araragi-kun is together with Senjougahara-san?
A while ago, you asked me about some things regarding Senjougahara-san.
Ah, I see. That's what it is.
Your imagination will make even the girls who like yaoi admit defeat.
Yaoi? What's that?
It's an acronym for "No climax, no punch line, deep meaning."
Sounds like you're lying.
It's okay. I will go and research it.
You really are serious.
It'd be bad if I've disturbed you guys. I will leave now.
Sorry to bother you. Say hi to Senjougahara-san for me.
Like I said, you have misunderstood me.
I just remembered, Hanekawa. May I ask you something?
Do you know where the house of a person called Tsunade-san is?
Tsunade-san?
I don't know.
There's something that Hanekawa doesn't know?
Didn't I tell you before?
It's not that I know everything. It has to be within the boundaries of what I know.
As for the others, I don't know anything.
I see.
I'm sorry that I couldn't meet your expectations.
It's nothing.
Well this time really is good bye.
May 14th, Sunday. 14 hours, 15 minutes, and 30 seconds
was the instant I got my hands on Senjougahara's mobile number.
Seriously, I get a rare feeling of laziness on a Sunday morning, and you still come to bother me.
Tsundere-chan's really mean.
Tsundere-chan? Are you referring to Senjougahara?
But by the way, within such a short period of time you were able to encounter such a strange thing.
The one who encountered it isn't me.
Really?
The one who encountered the snail is a child called Hachikuji Mayoi.
Oh, Hachikuji Mayoi?
I see. Understood, understood.
Hachikuji is the fifth chapter of The Tale of Shinonome.
Hanekawa also said the same thing.
What's the matter, Tsundere-chan?
What's wrong, Oshino?
Ah... Hmm...
Huh?
Araragi-kun is really useless.
Huh? What are you saying?
To actually make Tsundere-san so worried...
Won't this make her feel responsible?
Ah, to get Senjougahara involved into this, I also feel very sorry.
I don't mean that. Seriously...
Araragi-kun, your situation together with the President and Tsundere-chan makes it three situations.
Directly after, you became involved in this strange case.
That's why you've become arrogant, isn't it?
I didn't mean it that way.
Furthermore, whenever you encounter a strange thing, there won't always be a person like me by your side.
Normally, this would be impossible.
I also don't think a situation like this can be solved through the phone.
I thought that the situation was simple.
And to actually let a ripe, young girl come alone into a strange man's place...
I don't think that's proper.
But you wouldn't do anything, right?
Under normal circumstances, it should be a happy thing to be trusted.
But Tsundere-chan isn't like you who has that much trust in me.
Wait, wait. I won't do anything.
Put down that stapler, Tsundere-chan.
Stapler?
Oh, that really frightened me.
Tsundere-chan really is a horrifying Tsundere-chan.
Eh...
Indeed, I'm still not used to speaking on the phone.
It's hard to say.
What do you mean by that?
Then let's do this: I will tell Tsundere-chan the strategy to deal with that lost snail.
In the meantime, you shall stay there.
Strategy?
Will it be all right to ask someone to relay it?
Does it require a ceremony like Senjougahara's?
No. A snail is not as troublesome as a crab.
And it's not a god.
If I were to say, it would be a kind of demon or spirit.
Spirit?
By the way, do you happen to know of...
Hachijuuhakkasho of Shikoku and Sanjuusansho of Saigoku?
I know enough.
Hachikuji is of that type.
But think. "89" can also be pronounced as "misfortune."
Because of this sort of explanation, the name Hachikuji will slowly vanish.
So, it's that sort of connection.
Once you understand that piece of history, take a look at the name Hachikuji Mayoi.
What do you think?
Do you feel the sharp increase in meaning giving you a headache?
Sharp increase in meaning?
If you had felt it from the beginning, it would have been good.
So what if you feel that?
I will give the details to Tsundere-chan.
Good bye.
Okay.
But it would be nice if Tsundere-chan told you properly.
Eh?
What does he mean?
So that's that. Hachikuji.
It seems like there's a way.
From my impression, it doesn't sound like a conversation which found a way.
Putting that aside, Araragi-san.
What?
I'm hungry.
I'm Karen.
I'm Tsukihi.
Karen-chan, is it true under the rule of the cherubs, "cos-pos" is forbidden?
What's more scary is that helping is banned too.
And confessing is also forbidden?
Their ban-this-forbid-that match is way messed up.
So strict...
Well, they have a weapon with them.
But for me, their protectors are scarier than weapons.
Well, like you don't really need protection over there...
You're so overly safe it's actually scary!
Now then, time for our first nightly quiz!
It's our fourth time!
Speaking of cellphone ring tones...
It really has that feeling of a cellphone...
It's forbidden for a phone to ring on the train.
It might disturb the other passengers!
That obviously needs to be prohibited.
Just please keep your ringtone permanently turned off!
Please hand out the quiz.
Next time, Mayoi Snail Part 3.
Could we see the ringtone of the cellphone?
Can it be seen?